(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T23:23:20.383232",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
What's up!
I am Chaos, the End of Events,
a steel rose trapped in a cage of ice, your best red Hakos,
from hololive English -Promise-!
Witness me!
やったー！
Yay!
Happy 5 years, everyone!
5年？！ヤバくないっすか？
5 years?! Isn't that crazy?
ちょっとみんな、ヤバいっすね、5年。
Everyone, 5 years is insane.
Thank you so much for joining me today for my 5th anniversary stream!
I can't believe it's been 5 years.
We're also in a very nostalgic place!
いや、ここもね、ちょっと懐かしい場所に来ましたよね？
Yeah, we've come to a nostalgic place too, haven't we?
あの、this is the stage from my 3D debut stream,
Um, this is the stage from my 3D debut stream,
and I thought it'd be fitting to return back here for my big 5th!
Yes, back in the Fun Zone. Back in the Fun Zone.
We're gonna be hanging out with some awesome guests!
I can't believe some of the guests that, um, very graciously agreed to appear today.
I can't believe some of the guests who, um, very graciously agreed to appear today.
Uh, maybe some games, maybe some singing,
and that's not all!
As you may or may not already know, huge announcements,
with an S,
are coming your way, so make sure you stick to the very end!
えっと、まあ今日ですね、5周年お祝いということなんで、
Um, well today, since we're celebrating my 5th anniversary,
えっと、ゲストさんも、あの、すごいゲストさんが来てくれてますので、
um, we have some really amazing guests joining us,
本当自分も信じられないくらい、えっと、楽しみにしてます。
so I'm really looking forward to it to the point even I can't believe it.
ちょっとゲームやったりとか、まあ歌もね、ちょっと、あるかな？ちょっと分かんないすけど、あっ、と！
We'll play some games, and, well, maybe some singing too? I'm not sure, but oh, and!
重大発表もたくさんありますので、
There are lots of huge announcements as well, so
最後まで見ててください！
please watch until the very end!
And please make sure to share your thoughts on the stream using...
#BaeBig5th!
BaeBig5th!
I'll be checking all your posts after the stream, so don't...
ベジタパイス！
Vegetapice!
えっとですね、配信の感想は
Well then, for your thoughts on the stream,
ハッシュタグ #BaeBig5th
use the hashtag #BaeBig5th
を使って、えっと、投稿してください！
and please share your posts!
配信が終わったら、僕もみんなもね、
Once the stream ends, both me and everyone else
投稿チェックするので、
will be checking your posts,
たくさんの感想を待ってますよー！
so we'll be waiting for lots of feedback!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
はっ！
Hah!
Without further ado, let's jump right into our first segment!
行こう！
Let's go!
[Bae-gemite Extravaganza!! Hakos Baelz 5th Anniversary Stream]
- ベジタ！ - パーイス！
- Vegeta! - Pice!
Happy 5th Anniversary!
イェーイ！
Yay!
- Celebrate, celebrate! - おめでとう！
- Celebrate, celebrate! - Congrats!
- ベジタ！ - パーイス！
- Vegeta! - Pice!
Happy for you, Rat.
I'm so happy I'm with all my friends today!
ちょ、あの、自己紹介お願いしてもいいですか？
Could you please introduce yourselves?
- 私？ - カリ！カリ！
- Me? - Calli! Calli!
Okay, okay. あー！
Okay, okay. Ah!
みなさん！It's me, Mori Calliope from hololive English -Myth-!
Everyone! It's me, Mori Calliope from hololive English -Myth-!
破滅はここです、Death Death! I'm Shinigami, reaper, songwriter...
Havoc is here, Death Death! I'm Shinigami, reaper, songwriter...
...and also best friend to Hakos Baelz! My best friend!
イェーイ！Hakos Baelz!
Yay! Hakos Baelz!
Yeah! That's this!
チワッス！
Chiwassu!
I'm Subaru! ホロライブJP セカンドジェネレーション！
I'm Subaru from hololive JP 2nd Generation!
アンド！
And...
- ベストフレ... - Best friend! Hey!
- Best frien... - Best friend! Hey!
Wait, wait!
You said, you said I'm your best friend, Baelz Hakos!
You said I'm your best friend, Baelz Hakos!
So you're not my best friend, you're HER best friend?!
えっと、まあ、あの、ベストフレンド、みんなベストフレンドです！
Um, well, best friend... everyone is my best friend!
- ベストフレンドだって！ - 誰がベストフレンドなのよ？
- She said best friend! - Who is your best friend?
アンド！そして！そして！
And! And next!
Hi! Good morning, afternoon, evening! WAH!
I'm Ninomae Ina'nis from Holo English Myth.
I also wanna be Bae's best friend.
- ベストフレンド！ - 流石！
- Best friend! - As expected!
イェーイ！WAH!
Yay! WAH!
こやっぴー！ホロライブ 4th Generation、常闇トワ様でーす！
Koyappi! From hololive 4th Generation, it's Tokoyami Towa-sama!
イェーイ！トワ様！
Yay! Towa-sama!
私こそが、ベェのナンバーワン・ベストフレンドです！
I am Bae's number one best friend!
No, no, no, no, no!
Well, all of my best friends are here!
え、みんながベスト、え、うれしい！
Everyone is the best, I'm so happy!
- ウチがナンバーワン！勝負するぞ！ - I will fight you.
- I'm number one! Let's settle this! - I will fight you.
この子ナンバーワン。
This girl is number one.
えっ？
Huh?
この子がナンバーワン！
This girl is number one!
- でっけぇ！ - ベジマイト？
- It's huge! - Bae-gemite?
- オーマイガー！ - ベジマイトいるし。 - Big Bae.
- Oh my god! - There's Vegemite. - Big Bae.
でっけぇー！
So big!
これ何？What is this? What is this なんですけど。
What is this? What is this, though?
これ、あの、ベージマイトです！なんと今日ですね、僕の5周年なんで、It's my 5th anniversary!
This is Bae-gemite! Today is my 5th anniversary!
I bring to you... Bae-gemite Extravaganza! Part 1!
僕のベージマイト大企画へようこそ！
Welcome to my big Bae-gemite project!
- また来た、ベジマイト！ - ベジマイト！
- Vegemite is here again! - Vegemite!
お前、ベジマイト好きすぎ！
You love Vegemite way too much!
はい！えっと、ベジマイト代表なんで、はい。
Yes! Well, I am the Vegemite ambassador, so yeah.
- お願いします！ - なるほどね！
- Please look forward to it! - I see!
えっと、まあ、一応説明しますが、はい！
Well, I'll explain just in case, yes!
BAE-GEMITE... It's inspired by the greatest food of all: Vegemite.
Packed with vitamin B, it truly is the ultimate spread!
In fact...
...it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that everyone in my country grew up eating it.
And today, I'd like all of my guests to experience the true greatness that is Vegemite first-hand.
これはなんとですね、我が国への誇りである！
This is, indeed, the pride of our country!
ねえねえ、Look, look, look Calli's face.
Hey, look, look, look at Calli's face.
Why?!
But why?!
Today we have a very special rendition of Bae-gemite...
Bae-gemite SHOWDOWN!
Showdown?!
ゲームをやりたいと思います！はい！
We're going to play a game! Yes!
Is it to decide the best friend?
- ベストフレンド決定戦？ - 決める？
- A best friend showdown? - Are we deciding?
- Here's the show! - やば！やば！
- Here's the show! - Crazy! Crazy!
えっと、ゲームをやって、whoever loses will discover that, you know, they might be missing something, you know?
We'll play a game, and whoever loses will discover that, you know, they might be missing something, you know?
Do you know what it is, Calli? Do you have any idea what they could be missing if they lose?
- Yeah, that's right! Nutrition! - Nutrition?!
栄養が足りてない？
Lacking nutrition?
もちろん負けた方がね、栄養が足りないってこと！
Of course, whoever loses means they're lacking nutrition!
あー！怪しい！
Ah! Suspicious!
僕はですね、やっぱりベジマイトで育てられたので、あの、僕に負けた人がちょっとね、
Because I was raised on Vegemite, whoever loses to me...
- ちょっと栄養を増やして... - Yeah, that explains a lot, right?
- ...needs to get some more nutrition... - Yeah, that explains a lot, right?
え、セイムトール？セイムトール？ニアリー・セイムトール！セイムトール！
Eh, same height? Same height? Nearly same height!
いやいやいや！こっちじゃなくて、これですよ、これ！
No no no! Not this height, this one! This!
- This is forging muscle. - Strong.
Oh god. / Not enough muscle! / なるほどね
Oh god. / Not enough muscle! / I see.
ってことです
That's what it is.
Is everyone ready? / I'm ready. / Ready! Ready!
Are you ready? Are you ready?
Bring it on, yeah. / Bring it on. / I guess we're ready.
じゃあ、The Stage of Trials! Manifest yourselves... Fun Zone!
Then, The Stage of Trials! Manifest yourselves... Fun Zone!
え？おお！ / なにこれ！
What? Whoa! / What is this?!
すごーい！ / 何これ！
Amazing! / What's this?!
I didn't know you could do that. That's crazy!
なんか急に出てきてるやん！
It suddenly just popped up!
そう、Bae の力です！
That's right, it's Bae's power!
おー、これが！ / レース？コース？
Oh, this is...! / A race? A course?
レース！
Race!
So, the game we're playing today is... the ultimate tricycle race!
Tricycle! Tricycle!
三輪車レース！ということで...
Tricycle race! And so...
ええー！イエーイ！
What?! Yay!
The rules are very simple. We'll all ride a tricycle and complete two laps around the course we've set up here in the Fun Zone...
And the challenge is to see if you can beat my time! 僕より早ければ、まあ、あの、勝つって感じです。
And the challenge is to see if you can beat my time! If you're faster than me, well, you win.
おー！ / Get a win, babe. Okay.
Ooh! / Get a win, babe. Okay.
Bae-gemiteを食べなくていいってことだもんね？
That means we don't have to eat Bae-gemite, right?
あ、まあ、うん。 / Wait, so if we all win, no one- / ま、まあ...
Ah, well, yeah. / Wait, so if we all win, no one- / W-Well...
まあ、一応な？ / うん、そうです！
Well, technically? / Yeah, that's right!
よーし、勝ったらな！ / Win-win. / Eat if you win, eat if you win...
All right, if we win! / Win-win. / Eat if you win, eat if you win...
If you win! If you win!
ということで、ちょっと早速始めたいと思いますが...
So, I'd like to get started right away, but...
準備いいですか？ / はい！オッケー！ / Everyone ready? / はい！
Are you ready? / Yes! Okay! / Everyone ready? / Yes!
じゃあ、先輩おふたり... お願いしたいと... 思います！
Well then, senpais... would you two please step forward!
来い、トワ！ / Tricycle, come on.
Come at me, Towa! / Tricycle, come on.
え、これぶー？ / Ladies, ladies, ladies...
Wait, is this "boo"? / Ladies, ladies, ladies...
オッケー、オッケー！ / オッケー、オッケー！
Okay, okay! / Okay, okay!
ぶー、オッケー！ / オッケー、オッケー！
Boo, okay! / Okay, okay!
トワには負けねえ！俺が勝つ！
I won't lose to Towa! I'm gonna win!
スバルのことは眼中にありません。自分との戦いです。
Subaru isn't even on my radar. This is a battle against myself.
ジャンケンしたいです！ / あ、そうです！ / Okay. They're gonna do...
I want to play Rock-Paper-Scissors! / Ah, right! / Okay. They're gonna do...
Scissors, paper, rock to see... / 内側が有利なんじゃないかなと、スバルさん考えまして。
Scissors, paper, rock to see... / Subaru-san figured the inside lane might be advantageous.
Yeah, whoever's on the inside gets an advantage... / So we're gonna do scissors, paper, rock to find out who gets to ride on the inside! じゃ、どうぞ！
Yeah, whoever's on the inside gets an advantage... / So we're gonna do scissors, paper, rock to find out who gets to ride on the inside! Go ahead!
Rock, Paper, Scissors, Shoot! / わ！うわー！
Rock, Paper, Scissors, Shoot! / Whoa! Argh!
イエーイ！
Yay!
Nice! / ナイスです！
Nice! / Nice!
じゃあ、トワ様が内側ですね？ / そういうことですね！
So Towa-sama gets the inside lane, right? / That's right!
じゃ、お二人からちょっと意気込みをお願いしていいですか？ / はい！
Well then, could both of you give us your words of determination? / Yes!
I'm a winner! / わー！ / Winner Subaru! / Winner!
I'm a winner! / Whoa! / Winner Subaru! / Winner!
Awesome! / ウィンナー？ハロー、ウィンナー！
Awesome! / Wiener? Hello, wiener!
That's nice. / ウィンナーじゃない！
That's nice. / Not a wiener!
I'm a winner! / パクってんじゃん！
I'm a winner! / You're ripping me off!
痛い！痛い！
Ow! Ow!
じゃあ、乗ってください！ / はい！
Now, please get on! / Yes!
Bae, Bae, Bae! This battle... ブー、オッケー？
Bae, Bae, Bae! This battle... is boo okay?
ブー、オッケー！ / ブー、オッケー！ / Boo okay? / Boo, okay.
Boo is okay! / Boo is okay! / Boo okay? / Boo, okay.
You can interfere with each other if you want! Friendly fire allowed! / Oh brother.
But, you just can't, uh, get off your tricycle. ちょっと、三輪車から降りる、降りるのはちょっとダメ、ダメ。 / あ、なるほどね。
But, you just can't, uh, get off your tricycle. You can't get off your tricycle, that's not allowed. / Ah, I see.
でも、妨害もオッケーです！ / 妨害もオッケー？！オッケーです！ / やばい、妨害される！
But interfering is okay! / Interfering is okay too?! It's okay! / Oh no, she's gonna sabotage me!
はい！準備いいですか？ / はい！ / じゃあ、行くよ！Here we go!
All right! Are you ready? / Yes! / Well then, here we go!
3, 2, 1, Go! / やばいやばい！
3, 2, 1, Go! / Oh shoot, oh shoot!
ちょっと待って！ / ちょ、まっ... / Subaru-senpai got you on the inside!
Wait a minute! / Wait a... / Subaru-senpai got you on the inside!
行け行け！
Go, go!
2回目！2回！ / Second lap!
Lap two! Lap two! / Second lap!
逃げて！ / You can do it! Damn!
Run away! / You can do it! Damn!
うわー！ / おらおらおら！
Whoa! / Take that, take that!
イエーイ！ / Goal!
Yay! / Goal!
行け、トワ様！行け行け！ / Go, Towa-sama!
Go, Towa-sama! Go, go! / Go, Towa-sama!
イエーイ！
Yay!
おめでとうございます！ / Congratulations!
Congratulations! / Congratulations!
I'm a winner. / I'm a wiener. / 違う、I'm winner! / Yeah, wieners.
I'm a winner. / I'm a wiener. / No, I'm a winner! / Yeah, wieners.
Well, technically it wasn't just a battle between them. 一応、タイムアタックなんで、ちょっと後で... / タイムアタックだな。
Well, technically it wasn't just a battle between them. It's technically a time trial, so later... / A time trial, right.
I feel like I'm really well prepared for this race. You know, I'm a four-times champ of Underworld University tricycle marathon yearly trial.
Win or lose, I get to eat Bae's cooking. Yeah.
All righty! Seems like Calli and Ina are all set! Are you two feeling confident?
Heart! / ごめんごめんごめん / ちっちゃいね、イナちゃん。イナちゃんちっちゃい。 / ちっちゃい！
Heart! / Sorry, sorry, sorry! / You're so small, Ina-chan. Ina-chan is small. / Small!
Yeah, Ina is wholesome. We'd never fight.
You guys ready? Can we get a, a one comment from the both of you, please?
私、勝つ。 / カツ？カツ？
I will win. / Cutlet? Cutlet?
It's not- it's not as funny. / カツ？カツ丼？ / あ、カツサンド。
It's not- it's not as funny. / Cutlet? Pork cutlet bowl? / Ah, cutlet sandwich.
勝つさんです
It's Katsu-san.
Yeah
勝つさんだ 勝つさんだ！ イナさんと勝つさん
It's Katsu-san, it's Katsu-san! Ina-san and Katsu-san.
Ina is hungry...
Ina's hungry? お腹空いた？
Ina's hungry? You're hungry?
Winner gets the Vegemite.
カツ丼？ カツを食え！ 周り「勝つさん」言いますけど…
Katsudon? Eat the katsu! Everyone's saying "Katsu-san," though...
カツ丼？ カツ丼、カツオ、カツ
Katsudon? Katsudon, katsuo, katsu.
カツ丼 カツ丼
Katsudon. Katsudon.
やばい、カメラ… 止めて！ 止めて！ 止めてて！
Oh no, camera... Stop it! Stop it! Keep it stopped!
もう全員… 準備オッケーですか？
Everyone... Are you guys ready?
Alright, we gotta decide who's in the inner, who's in the outer. That's right. We gotta decide.
Outside is apparently stronger, so whoever wins gets the outside. Yes.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot! Pa!
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot! Paper!
Rock! おー！ Calli!
Rock! Ohhh! Calli!
カリは外側
Calli gets the outside.
Which means... Yeah, I got a feeling Ina is still gonna win this one, though. I got a bad feeling about this one.
This position is best! Position is best? ホントか？
This position is best! Position is best? Really?
I don't know, I got a bad feeling about this one... 行ける行ける！
I don't know, I got a bad feeling about this one... You can do it, you can do it!
Alright, you guys ready?! Yeah!
Alright, here we go! Three, two...
One... Go!
うわ、速い！ すごい！ イナ！
Whoa, fast! Amazing! Ina!
イナ！ イナ！
Ina! Ina!
Out of my way!
イナ頑張れ！ イナ！ イナ！
Hang in there, Ina! Ina! Ina!
Out of my way! カリ！
Out of my way! Calli!
There will be no Vegemite for me! イナ！ ゴール！
There will be no Vegemite for me! Ina! Goal!
I'm in too! One more lap?
No one's supposed to be in front of me! カリ頑張れ！
No one's supposed to be in front of me! Hang in there, Calli!
Yeah! Finished! ゴール！
Yeah! Finished! Goal!
ゴール！
Goal!
That's the most exercise I've done in 2 years. 筋肉痛…
That's the most exercise I've done in 2 years. Muscle pain...
イナ！ イナ大丈夫？ Are you okay?
Ina! Ina, are you okay? Are you okay?
Are you okay? I'm okay.
イナの足が… イナの足が… Her knees...
Ina's legs... Ina's legs... Her knees...
Wow, with the four of them completing the race, I think we should announce their times...
...before I try it.
まあ、4人終わってたんで、タイムを発表したいと思います！
Well, since the four of them have finished, I'd like to announce the times!
おおー！ Let's go!
Ooh! Let's go!
じゃあ、最初はスバル先輩！ 何秒でしょうか！
Alright, first up is Subaru-senpai! What's my time?!
28.85秒！
28.85 seconds!
うわ、速！ 結構いいんじゃない？ これ！
Whoa, that's fast! Isn't that pretty good?!
速いっすね！ いいんじゃない、これ！
That is fast! Isn't that great?!
じゃあ、次はトワ様！ はい！ タイムは…
Alright, next up is Towa-sama! Yes! The time is...
35.63秒！
35.63 seconds!
結構速いんじゃない？ ちょっと速いっすよ
Isn't that pretty fast? That's kinda fast.
35.63 seconds.
次はCalli, okay, Calliope Mori, your time is 36.72!
Next is Calli, okay, Calliope Mori, your time is 36.72!
Yeah, so, I'm fast. ここ、上？
Yeah, so, I'm fast. Is this higher?
I'm first? I'm first?
え？ 速… え？ What?
Huh? Fast... Huh? What?
で、最後はイナ！ Your time is...
And last is Ina! Your time is...
38.44秒！
38.44 seconds!
ああー！ ああー！ でもさ…
Aah! Aah! But you know...
36.72, 38.44.
え、でもみんな速くね？ Yeah, ちょっと遅いね。 つまり…
Huh, but isn't everyone fast? Yeah, a little slow. Which means...
...Bae-chan, maybe you're also a little slow like we are.
Oh... 40秒ぐらいでお願いたいところか
Oh... Would we prefer around 40 seconds?
So, I have to beat... みんな食べれる場合だったら…
So, I have to beat... If it's a case where everyone gets to eat...
28点… まあ、28… 8を切れば…
28 point... well, 28... If you beat 28.8...
切ればいいってことっすよね そうそうそう
That means you just have to beat it, right? Right, right, right.
Will be faster than 28 seconds. どこに入るかだね、ベイズ。 そう
Will be faster than 28 seconds. Let's see where you place, Bae. Yeah.
Well, with that being said, it's my turn! Let's go! イエーイ！
Well, with that being said, it's my turn! Let's go! Yay!
ベジマイトパワーで驚異のタイムを見せられるか！？
[Can Vegemite power deliver a blazing fast time!?]
For Vegemite!
ということで、ベイズの準備ができたそうです！ やったー！
And with that, it looks like Bae is ready! Yay!
Let's go, Bae! おー！ なんか一番似合ってるわ！
Let's go, Bae! Oh! It suits you the most!
何で？ ジャストフィット！ ジャストフィット！ Just for you! Perfect for you.
Why?! Just fit! Just fit! Just for you! Perfect for you.
普段からだって乗ってるでしょ？ 普段乗ってんの？ 乗ってねえよ！ そんなの！
You ride it normally, don't you? Normally?! I don't ride this! No way!
Better than a bicycle. I know, right?! どうですか？ 意気込みをお願いします！
Better than a bicycle. I know, right?! How do you feel? Tell us your enthusiasm!
いや、もう全てはベジマイトのためである。 僕は勝つ！
Well, everything is for the sake of Vegemite. I will win!
So serious. For Vegemite. とんでもないよ
So serious. For Vegemite. Unbelievable.
ベジマイト好きすぎるんだよな She's speaking Japanese to impress them.
She likes Vegemite way too much. She's speaking Japanese to impress them.
ベジマイトから生まれたんじゃない？
Maybe she was born from Vegemite?
だから Bae？ あ、そういうこと！？ だから Bae！？
That's why Bae? Ah, is that why?! That's why Bae?!
だから Bae ですよ！ あ、そういうことなんですね！ 繋がったね！ なるほど
That's why I'm Bae! Ah, so that's it! It all connects now! I see.
どうせ勝つだし、大丈夫 めっちゃガチやん
I'm gonna win anyway, so it's fine. She's super serious.
そんなこと言ったらさ、トワがさ… あ、すいません
If you say that, then Towa will... Ah, excuse me.
すいません、ちょっと通ります。 通ります 渡ってもいいですか？
Excuse me, passing through. Passing through. Can I cross over?
踊ります！
We're dancing!
ああー！
Aaaah!
Sorry, you can't cross, there's been an accident, there's been an accident, sorry.
You can't cross here, sorry, go home.
Go home?! Go home?!
Go home like...
Go home やばい！
"Go home" is crazy!
ま、ということで、じゃあこれでね、順位決まりますから。
Well then, this will decide the rankings,
我々のベジマイトにどうなるかっていうのは、これで決まりますから。
and that will decide what happens with our Vegemite.
はい！準備はいいですか？
Yes! Are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
Here we go!
3, 2, 1, GO!
うわ、なんか... やばいやばい！マジ必死！
Whoa... Oh boy! She's so desperate!
やばいやばい、ガチの顔してる！
Oh no, she has a totally serious face!
Serious!
尻で進んでる！尻で進んでる！
She's moving with her butt! Moving with her butt!
速い速い！
Fast, fast!
Wait, wait, wait!
Finish!
Wait, done!
Done!
はー... セーフ！
Whew... Safe!
速すぎ取った！速すぎるだろ！
That was way too fast! Way too fast!
スーパー速いんですけど、これ！
That was super fast!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はー！じゃあ、発表行きますか！
Whew! Well then, shall we move on to the announcement?
はい！
Yes!
さっきの順番でどこを足すか... あ、さっきの順番ね！
Depending on that order, what we add... Ah, in that order!
僕のタイム、お願いします！
Time, please!
おおー！
Ooooh!
全員ベジマイト食べまーす！
Everyone is eating Vegemite!
Yeah! All right!
She's excited about that.
I'll eat it.
お調子者すぎる、マジで！
She's way too cocky, seriously!
She's a little too hyped about that.
We're going to prepare the... not a punishment, it's a, it's a prize!
いや、みんなもう僕の心の優勝なんで、もうこれはプレゼントです！
No, in my heart everyone is a winner, so this is a present!
プレゼント... なんか言ってる...
A present... She's just talking...
いいように言ってるだけだ！
You're just phrasing it nicely!
なんか言ってる...
She's just rambling...
なので、みんなちょっと待ってね！ We're going to get the place prepared to taste some Bae-gemite!
So everyone, please wait a moment! We're going to get the place prepared to taste some Bae-gemite!
Yay...
I'll get hyped, too. Let's go!
ベジマイト食べまーす！
Time to eat Vegemite!
The dishes are ready.
You know, when I first had these four enter,
I knew from the get-go they were lacking nutrition.
やっぱりね、この4人が入った瞬間に、もう分かってました。
As expected, the moment these four walked in, I already knew.
What are you talking about?
栄養が足りてない！
Lacking nutrition!
ええー？ 栄養が足りてない！
What? Lacking nutrition!
なので、こちらを準備しております。
Therefore, I have prepared this.
You know, everyone is lacking nutrition.
And what is the most important meal of the day?
That's right, breakfast!
朝ご飯は一番大事な食事なんで、
Breakfast is the most important meal,
今日は皆様に栄養たっぷり朝ご飯を用意しております。
so today I've prepared a nutritious breakfast for everyone.
Oh, great.
えっ、デリシャスなんですか？
Um, is it delicious?
Very delicious です！
It's very delicious!
Very delicious? ベリーデリシャス？
Very delicious? Very delicious?
You can take off the covers! オープン！
You can take off the covers! Open!
オープン！ うわー！ おおー！
Open! Whoa! Ooh!
We will... ちょっと1つずつご紹介させてください。
We will... Please let me introduce them one by one.
まずですね、あの生ベジマイトありますね。
First off, we have raw Vegemite.
これは後でね、トワ様とイナは食べたことないんで、
Towa-sama and Ina haven't eaten it before,
1回ちょっとね、生で...
so later, just a taste of it raw...
味見でね、ちょっとだけ。
Just a little bit for a taste test.
生ベジマイト... Oh, damn.
Raw Vegemite... Oh, damn.
で、健康的な朝ご飯を用意しております。
And I have prepared a healthy breakfast.
まずはね、パン。パンにベジマイトを塗っております。
First is bread. Spread with Vegemite on bread.
これはオーストラリアで定番の朝ご飯です。
This is a classic Australian breakfast.
This is a very traditional Australian breakfast with bread and Vegemite.
で、次参ります。味噌汁でございます！
Next up: we have miso soup!
When we speak of Japanese breakfast, we think of miso soup.
味噌汁ですね、朝ご飯と言えば。
Miso soup, speaking of breakfast.
まあ、本当に豪華朝ご飯と言ったら、お寿司ですね！
And when talking about a truly luxurious breakfast: sushi!
いや、朝から食わねえよ、寿司！
No one eats sushi for breakfast!
朝から寿司食わねえよ！
We don't eat sushi for breakfast!
I just need someone to agree with me that Vegemite and sushi is amazing!
ちょっとね、認めて欲しくて、寿司とベジマイト、マジで似合うんで！
I just want you to admit it—sushi and Vegemite go so well together!
嘘だ！ I don't think so.
No way! I don't think so.
え、どこにつけたの？ベジマイト。
Wait, where did you put the Vegemite?
ワサビみたいに、裏にちょっとつけてます。
Like wasabi, I put a little bit underneath.
マジで？！やばい！
Really?! That's crazy!
いや、ワサビの代わりにちょっと...
No, just a little bit instead of wasabi...
やばい、なんかこれオープンした瞬間から鼻がぐじゅぐじゅ言い出してきたんだけど、大丈夫？
Oh no, ever since we opened this, my nose started running, is this okay?
なので、ちょっとトワ様とイナは、ベジマイト初なんで、生で...
So since it's Towa-sama and Ina's first time with Vegemite, try it raw...
Would that like, get rid of the taste of any other food after?
No, no, no! Just a little bit. Have a little courage.
いただきます...
Bon appétit...
It's so salty. Try it, try it.
Okay, Towa-sama first. Oh, she's going for it.
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
え？普通？
Huh? It's normal?
ええ？めっちゃいい顔した！
What? That was such a great reaction face!
まあ、いけなくはない。
Well, it's not inedible.
ああー！ Nice, nice.
Aah! Nice, nice.
ちょっと、すげえな、さすがでございます。
Wait, that's intense. As expected.
いけなくはない！いけなくはない。なるほどですね。
"Not inedible"! Not inedible. I see.
はい、オッケーです。じゃあ次。
All right, okay! Next up.
Let's go, Ina!
Let's go!
Don't be scary! 恐れるな！
Don't be scared! Don't be afraid!
Don't be scary, don't be scary.
Don't be scary. It's good, it tastes so good.
Don't be scared. It's good, it tastes so good.
Okay. Miso, miso, miso.
行きます。
Here goes.
平気だよ！
You'll be fine!
美味しいでしょ！
Delicious, right?
行きます。
Here I go.
It's not that bad.
See! ああ、さすが！
See! Ah, as expected!
Not that bad, pretty good.
"Not that bad" equals "pretty good".
うん！美味しいでしょう？
Yeah! Delicious, right?
うん、悪くない。
Yeah, not bad.
悪くない！いける！
Not bad! It's totally fine!
But would you choose to eat it?
If I had absolutely no other side dishes, and only a bowl of rice...
Possibly.
おー！
Ooh!
じゃあちょっと、みんなの朝ご飯タイム行きますか？
Well then, shall we move on to everyone's breakfast time?
じゃあ最初、パンでお願いします！
Let's start with bread/toast, please!
いただきまーす！パンで。
Let's eat! Toast.
はい、いただきます。
Okay, thank you for the food.
See, it's good with bread.
See! 美味しいでしょう！美味しいですよね！
See! Delicious, right? It's tasty, isn't it!
You need bread though, or something.
うん、good!
Yeah, good!
See!
ん〜〜〜
Mmm...
どうした？どうした？
What happened? What's wrong?
This is breakfast.
しょっぱ！しょっぱい！
Salty! So salty!
It is pretty salty.
Yeah, it is pretty salty.
美味しいですよね？ほら、ほら！
It's good, right? Look, look!
ほら、全然バツじゃない！
See, it's not a penalty at all!
ちょっと味が濃い。
The flavor is a bit strong.
味は濃いっすね。まあそうですね。
The flavor is strong, yeah. That's true.
パン食った後にちょっと飲みたいんじゃないですか？
After eating bread, wouldn't you like something to drink?
飲みたい、飲みたい！
I do, I do!
じゃあ次はお味噌汁お願いします！
Then next, let's have miso soup, please!
Bread, three stars?
Three stars. Out of ten?
Out of five, haha, out of five, but I mean, yeah...
お味噌汁、お味噌汁！Miso soup!
Miso soup, miso soup! Miso soup!
You know, everyone keeps saying that Vegemite tastes like miso...
お味噌汁美味しい！
The miso soup is good!
おー！Good!
Ooh! Good!
ベリーグッド！ベリーグッド！
Very good! Very good!
Well, a yummy item.
Don't get mad, don't get mad, don't get mad at me.
Yo, she's gonna kill me.
I don't taste it in them. なんか味が...しない。
I don't taste it in them. I can't really... taste it.
普通のお味噌汁。うん、普通のお味噌汁。
It's just normal miso soup. Yeah, normal miso soup.
いや美味いでしょ？美味しいよ！
No, but it's tasty, right? It's good!
まる！これ合格です！
Pass! This is a pass!
あ、合格！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Ah, a pass! Thank you very much! Thank you!
最後きつ！
The last one looks rough!
いや、魚の方でちょっと食べて欲しいんですけど...
Well, I'd like you to try it with the fish, but...
いや、これヤバい！
No, this is crazy!
ヤバい！絶対美味しい！
Crazy! It's definitely delicious!
Calli? いただきます。
Calli? Thanks for the food.
You don't have to dip it in soy sauce.
That's not the fish!
卵！
Tamago!
Eat the salmon! Eat the salmon!
やだー！ I want tamago sushi!
No way! I want tamago sushi!
Don't dip it in soy sauce.
もう醤油につけなくて大丈夫です。
You don't need to dip it in soy sauce anymore.
醤油につけなくていいの？
We don't have to dip it in soy sauce?
いや、しょっぱいなんで。
Because it's already salty.
どう？Is it not good?
How is it? Is it not good?
It's fine.
おー！
Ooh!
はい次！次、次、次誰行きます？
Okay, next! Next, next, who's going next?
うわああ！いただきます！
Waaah! Thanks for the food!
あああー！なんか微妙...！
Ahhh! It's kind of iffy...!
いや、普通... え、なんか...
No, it's normal... Huh, somehow...
美味しい、美味しい！最初美味しいの顔してた！
It's delicious, delicious! At first you made a face like it was delicious!
Two stars.
Right? Two stars.
いい？では、いただきます。サーモン。
Ready? Well then, thanks for the food. Salmon.
そうだよね、分かるよ。
Right? I get you.
I think soとは、I think soだよ！
Saying "I think so" means "I think so"!
なんかこのBGMのタイミング...
The timing of this BGM...
ノーベジマイトじゃない？なんか。ベジマイト無く無い？
Isn't there no Vegemite on it? Like, is there no Vegemite?
ベジマイト無い。
There is no Vegemite.
There is no Vegemite. え、だからput on, on Vegemite.
There is no Vegemite. You need to put Vegemite on top!
え、でも今中に入れたよ？
Huh, but I put it inside just now?
中だと分からないんだって！
You can't tell if it's inside!
ちゃんと付けた方がいいと思うけど。
I think you should put it properly on top though.
上に！ダイレクト、ダイレクトベジマイトしないと！
On top! You have to do direct Vegemite!
そうだよね？そっち？
Right? That one?
そうそうそうそう！
Yes yes yes yes!
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
じゃあ、イカ。そうすると星2になるよ。
Then, squid. If you do that, it'll become two stars.
イカ。行きます。 Let's go!
Squid. Here goes. Let's go!
どう？どう？どう？
How is it? How is it? How is it?
This is so cute.
Why?
吐いてもいいかな？ 大丈夫っすよ。
Can I spit it out? Go ahead.
何、何言いましたか？どうしました？
What, what did she say? What happened?
なんか、お寿司を買って、冷蔵庫に...
Like, you buy sushi, put it in the fridge...
ちょっと入れて...
for a bit...
入ったのを忘れて 普通に食べるような感じの...
Forgetting it was in there, it tastes like...
味がする。
...how you'd normally eat it.
それさ、微妙寿司？ 寿司...
Wait, questionable sushi? Sushi...
寿司飯やん！ 寿司飯！
It's sushi rice! It's sushi rice!
寿司や！ でもその...
It is sushi! But...
ベジマイトの匂いが...
...the smell of the Vegemite...
すっごく美味しいな！
...is super delicious!
やったー！
Yay!
What star? 3 star?
What star? Three star? Four star?
Don't say out of how many.
How many star? How many?
How many stars? How many?
5。
Five.
Five stars! Five?!
Five stars out of five.
Out of 10? Out of 10? No!
5 out of 5ですよね！
That's five out of five, right?!
よっしゃー！
Alright!
僕が食べた時めっちゃ美味しかったんすけど、なんで？
When I ate it, it was super delicious, so why?
うーん、ハコスのTongue is crazyなのか...
Hmm, maybe Hakos's tongue is crazy...
まあ、味は... まあまあ、一旦良しとして...
Well, setting the taste aside for now...
栄養はたっぷり入ってます！
...it's packed with plenty of nutrition!
Yeah, it's nutritious.
ちょっとね、前に... 行きましょうか。ちょっとみんな...
Let's, you know, move forward. Everyone...
前に出る。
Step forward.
Thank you for the food.
You're welcome.
ごちそうさまでした！
Thank you for the meal!
いやーちょっとね...
Man, well...
どっちがいい？ どっちがいい？ OK.
Which way is better? Which way is better? OK.
ほらほらもう栄養、栄養の成果！
Look, look, it's the results of the nutrition!
栄養ダンス！ 栄養ダンスか！
Nutrition dance! A nutrition dance?!
いやー本当に楽しかったです！ ありがとうございました！
Man, that was really fun! Thank you so much!
Thank you! Thank you.
I'm so happy that all my, you know, lovely friends could join me...
Best friends! Best of friends!
...could join me in celebrating my 5th anniversary.
And, you know, not only I get to celebrate it with Vegemite...
...but also with these lovely ladies.
And also, I have a huge announcement!
ビッグ... ビッグアナウンス？
A big... big announcement?
ビッグアナウンスがあります！
I have a big announcement!
Big what? Big...?
ビッグアナウンスメントが来ましたので、ちょっとみんな一緒に、「どうぞ」で言ってくれますか？
Since the big announcement is here, could everyone say "take a look" together with me?
OK! OK! よいしょ！
OK! OK! Here we go!
If you're all ready, it's time for the huge announcement! Please take a look at this!
どうぞー！
Here it is!
What moves thy heart?
What is thy true desire?
The fallen crown awaits from the shadows...
Her time has come,
No one will ever question her rule again.
2026.12.01
Hakos Baelz
1st Concert
I'll run the world, don't be afraid, it ain't a thing if you win
満たされないパワー 暴走した
An unsatisfied power went wild
Give me more, I need more, oh you'll be begging on the floor
自分次第の生涯 僕のShowtime
A lifetime up to oneself, it's my Showtime
Offer up thy soul and kneel.
For those who bow before her will...
WITNESS HER LEGACY!
あああ！
Ahhh!
I finally told you!
I can't believe it guys, I did it!
I am finally holding my very own solo concert!
ソロライブ決定です！ やったー！
Solo concert confirmed! Yay!
Ah! I'm so happy!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so very much!
It's gonna be happening on December 1st of this year...
...and the venue is none other than Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
えっとなんと、12月1日、決定されました！ ソロライブです！
And on December 1st, it's been confirmed! It's a solo live!
えっ東京のKanadevia Hallで開催決定です！
And it's confirmed to be held at Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
もう決定... 決定ですよみんな！ やったー！
It's already confirmed... It's confirmed everyone! Yay!
えっ、ライブのタイトルは『REGALIA』。
And the title of the live is "REGALIA".
This is the title of the live, REGALIA.
I chose this title because I wanted this live to, you know, be, or to become a...
...symbol of my journey so far, and hopefully
a symbol for what is yet to come for
a Bae take... course, you know?
ええと、ま、今回のライブタイトルは「REGALIA」です。
Um, well, the title of this live concert is "REGALIA."
このライブはね、僕のこれまでの活動を象徴にするぞという...
This concert, with the intention of making it a symbol...
意思を込めて、このタイトルにしました！
...of my journey and activities so far, is why I chose this title!
ええと、チケットやグッズの情報は後日発表しますので、もう少々...少し待っててください。
Um, information about tickets and merchandise will be announced at a later date, so please wait just a little longer.
Tickets and goods will be announced later on.
Please get hyped!
I did it! I did it!
And there's more!
In celebration of my first ever solo live,
I am so happy to announce that my second album, "Mirror Mirror",
is on its way!
Pre-orders will open today from 9:00 PM JST on the hololive production official shop.
そして、ええと、ま、ライブに向けて、セカンドアルバムも、あの、出ます！
And, um, leading up to the live concert, my second album is also coming out!
「Mirror Mirror」というリリースが、あの、決定しました！
The release of "Mirror Mirror" has been confirmed!
ええと、日本時間で今日23日の夜9時から、
Starting from 9:00 PM tonight on the 23rd, JST,
ええと、ホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで、あの、ま、受注開始されます！
pre-orders will open on the hololive production official shop!
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much! Truly, thank you.
Um, this album is so special to me. Uh, it includes many songs.
Um, actually I wrote the lyrics of most of the songs on this album,
uh with the theme of reflection, facing oneself,
and this album was a project where I pushed myself to explore even more ways to express myself as an artist.
ええとなんとですね、今回のアルバムの曲は大体全部、歌詞の方は自分で書いてました。
And amazingly, I wrote the lyrics for almost all the songs on this album myself.
ええと、まあ、リフレクション、自己との向き合いっていうテーマにして、
Um, with the theme of "reflection" and facing oneself,
ま、アーティストとしてのさらなる表現力をええと追求したい作品となってます！
it's a project where I sought to further pursue my expressive power as an artist!
Uh, it also comes with a lot of uh album bonuses.
You'll receive a special message letter with my signature, an original mirror sticker, and an artbook-style lyric booklet.
I'll be signing every single one of them, so please get it!
あとね、アルバム購入特典もあります！
Also, there are album purchase bonuses!
サイン付きのスペシャルメッセージ（日本語版も英語版もあります）、オリジナルミラーステッカーもあります！
A special message letter with my signature (available in Japanese and English), and an original mirror sticker!
アートブック型のあの歌詞カードもあります！
There's also an artbook-style lyric card booklet!
ええ、もう買ってくれ-てくれたみんなもう、サイン、サインをしますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
For everyone who purchases it, I will be signing them, so please look forward to it!
Uh you can check the shop directly from YouTube,
um and both the album shipments and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd JST.
So get hyped! Stay tuned! There's a lot yet to come!
ええと、YouTubeからショップへアクセスできるので、ぜひチェックしてください。
Um, you can access the shop directly from YouTube, so please check it out.
また、発送と、え、デジタルリリースは11月2日の予定となっております。
Also, shipments and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd.
楽しみにしといてください！
Please look forward to it!
そして、そして、そして！
And, and, and!
Uh, I may have mentioned before that there is a new song releasing today, and that is right!
Right after this stream, the music video for "I found me",
which is a very, very special song that is actually the first song I ever wrote from scratch, will be releasing—will be premiering after this stream!
ええと、この配信が終わった時、ちょっと、あの、アルバムからの1曲「I found me」のMVが公開します！
Um, after this stream ends, the MV for "I found me," a song from the album, will be premiered!
この曲は僕にとってめっちゃ大事な曲なんで、そして初めて一から書いた曲なんで（あの歌詞の方ね）。
This song is super important to me, and it's the first song I ever wrote from scratch (the lyrics, that is).
なのでぜひぜひ、プレミア公開、よろしくお願いします！
So please, make sure to check out the premiere!
The MV will be the opening video for my segment during YouTube Music Weekend!
Tada! That's a lot! I'm so happy!
My fifth anniversary and I get to be part of YouTube Music Weekend!
Um so it'll be the opening video for my section which starts at 1:15 PM JST, so make sure to check it out!
このMVはこの後13時15分からスタートするYouTube Music Weekendで僕のオープニングパートにもなってるので、
This MV will also be the opening part of my segment for YouTube Music Weekend starting at 1:15 PM,
ぜひぜひこれもチェックしてください！
so please be sure to check this out as well!
That is us!
That was a lot of announcements.
Are you guys, are you guys proud of me? I got this out alive!
You guys know why I've been so busy now!
I've been busy... I've been already doing a lot of prep for this amazing event that's happening,
and I'll be sharing more details about the concert at a later date, so I really hope you look forward to it!
ええと、まあ、最近ちょっと僕ね、あの、疲れてるプラスめっちゃ忙しくなった理由もこれになりますので、
Um, well, this is the reason why I've been a bit tired recently and super busy,
本当に頑張りますので、あの、楽しみにしててください！
so I'll really do my best, and please look forward to it!
All right! With that being said, I think it's time to move on to the next segment!
ちょっと次のコーナーに行きたいと思います！
I'd like to move on to the next segment!
Welcome to...
ベジマイトコンテスト〜！イエーイ！
The Bae-gemite Concoctions! Yeah!
イエーイ！イエイ、イエイ！
Yeah! Yeah, yeah!
イエーイ！うおおお！
Yeah! Uoohhh!
見てる方も、I think everyone knows, but 一応自己紹介お願いしていいですか？
To everyone watching... I think everyone knows, but could you please introduce yourselves?
はい！もちろんございます。
Yes! Of course.
じゃあ私から。えー、ホロスターズの夕刻ロベルです！本日はよろしくお願いいたします！
Then starting with me. I'm Yukoku Roberu from HOLOSTARS! Pleased to be here today!
イエーイ！
Yay!
なんか不穏な感じがね、しますけど。
I'm sensing somewhat ominous vibes, though.
そうですね。
Right.
はい、怖いです。
Yes, it's scary.
怖くないね。
It's not scary!
あ、怖くないもんね？怖くないです。頑張りたいと思います。よろしくお願いします！
Ah, it's not scary, right? Not scary at all. I'll do my best. Looking forward to this!
お願いします！そして？
Welcome! And next?
はい！あの、理由も分からず呼び出されて、
Yes! Um, I was summoned here without knowing why,
仕事だと思って来たら、なんだか不穏なスタジオでした。石川界人です。声優です。よろしくお願いします！
and showed up thinking it was a regular gig, only to find a sketchy studio. I'm voice actor Kaito Ishikawa. Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！お願いしまーす！
Nice to meet you! / Welcome!
そんな我々からもちょっとベーちゃんに言わなきゃいけないことあります！ / ありますね！
And we also have something we need to say to you, Bae-chan! / We sure do!
行きましょう！せーの！
Let's do it! Ready, set...
ソロライブ開催決定、おめでとーーー！
Congratulations on your solo live concert announcement!
ありがとうございます！ / すごいことよ！
Thank you so much! / That's incredible!
あ、泣いちゃった？あーららら。
Ah, are you crying? Oh, my, my.
嬉しい... / 嬉しいな。いや、すごいことよ！おめでとう！
I'm so happy... / Happy tears. Truly, it's amazing! Congrats!
ありがとうございます。 / 本当におめでとう！
Thank you so much. / Huge congratulations!
なんか、一VTuberファンとしてさ、ソロライブっていうのは夢じゃん！
As a fellow VTuber fan, having a solo live concert is the ultimate dream!
夢ですね！本当にありがとうございます。
It really is a dream! Thank you so much.
なんかもう熱いわ！ / 泣いてる。 / ありがとうございます！
Man, it really gets you emotional! / She's crying. / Thank you so much!
本当に、素晴らしい、本当。
Truly wonderful, really.
えっと、今日はね、チャレンジをやりたいと思います！
So today, we're going to take on a challenge!
チャレンジ！いいですね、挑戦。
A challenge! Sounds great, a challenge.
チャ、チャレンジですね、チャレンジ。
A cha... challenge, yes, a challenge.
Today we've invited these two for a challenge called "The Bae-gemite Concoctions"! We've come up with some absolutely outrageous Vegemite concoctions...
まあ、ロベさんと界人さんはもうベジマイトのことはご存知しておりますよね？ / もちろん。
Well, Robe-san and Kaito-san, you both already know all about Vegemite, right? / Of course.
なんか当たり前のように口にしてるけど、そのなんか... / 大好物？
You talk about it like it's totally normal, but... / Favorite food?
我々にとっては、その、呪詛みたいなもんだから、その... その、そう、あの、怖いのよ、結構。
For us, it's practically a curse, you know... So, yeah, it's actually pretty terrifying.
ベジマイトって言ったら、まあロベさんですよね？
When you think of Vegemite, you think of Robe-san, right?
正直このベジマイトという道を作ってしまった発端の人物かもしれない。
Honestly, I might be the very origin that paved the road of Vegemite.
そうです！
Exactly!
あの、そう、ベーちゃんにそのベジマイトっていうものがあるよって教えてもらって、僕がその実食配信みたいなのをするようになったんですよ。
Bae-chan told me about Vegemite, and that led me to do a stream tasting it live.
そこから始まった、この地獄は。多分。
And that's where this whole hell began. Probably.
え、そして被害者が... / 被害者たちが生まれていった。
And then the victims... / More and more victims were born.
そう、で、一緒にね、その配信で食レポみたいな配信もしたことがあって。
Yeah, and we even did a stream together where we did a food review of it.
で、それ以来なんで、こいつと対峙するのは3、4年ぶりぐらいになりますが、まあ...
And I haven't faced this thing since then, so it's been about 3 or 4 years, but well...
じゃあもう味も忘れちゃってそうだもんね？
Then you must have forgotten how it tastes by now, right?
うん、あのね、こびりついてる。
No, see... it's burned into my memory.
4年経っても消えない。 / 言い方！ / 味の記憶がこびりついてる。
Even after 4 years, it hasn't faded. / Watch your phrasing! / The taste is seared into my brain.
うん、だから非常にね、怖さはあるけど、まあでもね、楽しみですよ。
Yeah, so there's definitely fear, but hey, I'm looking forward to it.
も、もっと元気そうに。 / 楽しみです！
S-sound a bit more energetic! / I'm looking forward to it!
イエーイ！すごい楽しみ！食べたい！
Yay! So excited! Can't wait to eat!
そして界人さん、あの、ベジマイトエピソードっていうことはありますか？
And Kaito-san, do you have any Vegemite stories?
ああ、ベジマイトエピソードですか？非常に素晴らしい、あの、食材ですよね。ええ。
Ah, Vegemite stories? It's a truly wonderful ingredient, isn't it? Yes.
もらってましたよね？ベーちゃんから。 / ええ。
You received some from Bae-chan, right? / Yes.
ホロごえで一緒になったときに、ベーちゃんからありがたいお土産を、あんたもらってたよね？ / ええ。
When you two were on "HoloGoe" together, you got that generous souvenir from Bae-chan, didn't you? / Yes.
番組収録終了時にね、あの、わざわざ楽屋にご挨拶いただいて、
When we wrapped up filming the show, she took the time to visit my dressing room to greet me,
「なんて丁寧な方なんだろう」と。「素敵な方だな」っていうふうに思って、
and I thought, "What a polite person she is. What a lovely person."
受け取って、「これお土産です」と。「あ、ありがとうございます。あれですか？
Then I accepted it and she said, "Here is a souvenir." I said, "Ah, thank you. Is it...
なんかお菓子かなんかですか？」って。「あ、ベジマイトです」って。
some kind of snacks or sweets?" and she replied, "Ah, it's Vegemite."
一応食べましたよ。 / おー、えらい！
I did try it, by the way. / Oh, good on you!
食べました？！ / 食べました、ちゃんと食べました。 / それはえらいですよ。
You ate it?! / I did, I properly tasted it. / That's truly commendable.
「なんて素晴らしい食材なんだろう」って思いましたね。 / ありがとうございます！
I thought, "What an incredible food product this is." / Thank you so much!
いや、素晴らしいんだよ、やっぱ。ベジマイトっていうのは。 / ええ、素晴らしい。 / ベジマイトは素晴らしいです。
Truly magnificent after all. Vegemite is. / Yes, magnificent. / Vegemite is amazing.
ちょっとね、記憶もあんまないと思いますので、ちょっと先、生で食べさせてもらいます。 / あ、いや...
Since I bet your memories of it are a bit foggy, first I'll have you try it raw. / Ah, wait...
I gotta refresh their memories on the taste, so we do have Vegemite prepared in front of us.
大丈夫、大丈夫。 / いや、大丈夫じゃないです。 / あの、大丈夫だよ。
We're fine, we're good. / No, you're not fine! / Seriously, we're okay.
あの、お願いってわけじゃなくて、5周年なんで、命令です！
Um, it's not a request. Since it's my 5th year celebration, this is an order!
食えと。 / 食え！
"Eat it." / Eat it!
ソロライブも決まってるしな！ / そうです！お願いします！
Well, her solo live is announced after all! / That's right! Please do it!
こんなめでたい人の命令じゃあ... / そうです！
If it's an order from someone celebrating such a big milestone... / That's right!
あ、怖い！ / はい、じゃあ、せーの！
Ah, scary! / Okay then, ready, set...
ちょっと待って... / 怖い... 乾杯！ / 乾杯！ / マジで怖い！
Wait a second... / Scary... Cheers! / Cheers! / Seriously terrifying!
うわあ...
Uwaah...
うわ、美味しい！
Wow, delicious!
美味ちぃ！ / うまいねー！ / すごい！
Delish-ish! / So tasty! / Incredible!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you guys okay?
大丈夫そう、あ、もう飲み切っちゃいました！
Looks like he's fine—wait, he already chugged all his water!
はい、石川界人 has finished 1 bottle of water. えっ、早っすね！
Yes, Ishikawa Kaito has finished 1 bottle of water. That was fast!
うわあ、お水にとても合うなあ！
Wow, it goes so well with water!
ああー...
Ahhh...
あー、幸せ
Ah, I'm so happy!
はぁー...
Haaah...
大丈夫でしょうか？ちょっとあの、ロベ先輩の顔がエグいです。
Are you guys okay? Robe-senpai's face looks rough.
泣いてる。
He's crying.
泣いてます？！
He's crying?!
ほぼ泣いてる。
He's practically crying.
なんで？
Why?
美味すぎて...
It was too delicious...
美味すぎてな？わかるよ。
Too delicious, right? I get it.
Somebody is crying.
美味すぎてね。涙が止まらないね。
Too delicious, yeah. The tears just won't stop.
進行し...あの、多分両端死んでる...
Moving on... Both sides look like they're dead...
多分両端が死んでると思って。
Just think of both ends as being dead.
ああ...
Ahh...
はい、じゃあ説明行きます。えーと、
Alright, let's move on to the explanation! Um...
We have the Vegemite concoctions,
so it is a tasting—not competition, but I'd say tasting event.
Uh, to explain how it works,
before today, Robe-senpai, Akira, and I each came up with an ingredient that we thought would pair well with Vegemite.
And using all of our ideas, ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator—pro!
And using all of our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator—pro!
ええ？！ / あ、そう！
Eh?! / Ah, right!
A professional food coordinator has created each dish with great care,
and we're gonna taste all of them and decide who came up with the best Vegemite concoction!
なるほど。我々が選んだ食材でプロの方が、
I see. So with the ingredients we chose, a pro...
すごく美味しくベジマイトを使って料理してくださってると。
...has cooked something delicious using Vegemite.
はい！ / なるほど。
Yep! / I see.
ということで... / それ信じられるの？
And so... / Can you really believe that?
え？いや、でもベジマイト元々美味しいんだよ。
Eh? But Vegemite is delicious to begin with.
ああ、そうだった。ごめんごめん。 / プロだからね。
Ah, right. My bad. / They're pros, after all.
プロだもんね！
They're pros, after all!
ベジマイト美味しいしね。
Vegemite is delicious too.
うん、美味しい！ / 設定が...
Yeah, delicious! / The backstory is...
なので、まあ美味しいプラス美味しいイコール美味しいじゃないですか。
So, tasty plus tasty equals tasty, right?
ああ、そうですね！ / 美味しい。 / はい。
Ah, that's right! / Tasty. / Yes.
美味しい。 / 美味しい。
Tasty. / Tasty.
ということで、あの、お互い何選んだか全くわかんないんで... / 全く知らない、マジで。
So, neither of us has any idea what the other picked... / I have no clue at all, seriously.
We don't know what the other has chosen, so it's going to be a surprise to us as well.
まあ、早速始めようか。
Well then, shall we jump right in?
あ、なるほど。 / 始めます？
Ah, I see. / Shall we start?
いいですよ。一旦休憩時間ほしいかな...
Sure. Though I kind of want a break first...
休息？！早いですよ！
A break?! It's too early for that!
胃の中でベジマイトが大暴れしてるんだわ。
The Vegemite is raging inside my stomach.
なん、すごいよね。生きてる、これは。
It's incredible, isn't it? It's alive.
まあ、最初ちょっと、何を選んだかロベ先輩に聞きたくて。
Well, first I want to ask Robe-senpai what he chose.
じゃ、僕から行きますか？ / 最初にお願いします。
Shall I go first? / Please start us off.
わかりました。えー、では僕が選んだ食材はこちらでございます！
Understood. Well then, the ingredient I chose is this!
牛タンです！
It's beef tongue!
おおー！ / おおー！ / 完璧！
Ohh! / Ohh! / Perfect!
牛タンです。やっぱり、 / いいね！
Beef tongue. After all... / Nice!
しょっぱいじゃないですか、ベジマイトって。
Vegemite is salty, right?
で、これをお肉に合うんじゃないかなと思ったんですよ、僕。
So I thought it would go really well with meat.
そこに、単純に僕が牛タン食べたかったのもありまして。
Plus, I simply just wanted to eat beef tongue.
アンケートを書いた時にね。
When filling out the survey, right?
なので今回牛タンを選ばせていただきました。
So this time, I chose beef tongue.
美味しくならないわけがない！ / 確かに。
There's no way it won't be good! / True.
なるほどですね。
Indeed.
美味しいと思います。
I think it'll be delicious.
確かに焼肉系は美味そう。 / ね！
Yakiniku-style meat definitely sounds tasty. / Right?!
Gyutan which is beef tongue, it is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, it's meat.
Gyutan, which is beef tongue, is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, it's meat.
Vegemite is salty, would be a good pairing, one would think.
なるほどですね。素晴らしい！ / 素晴らしいでしょ、これ。
I see. Wonderful! / It's wonderful, isn't it?
これはちょっとプロの方にお願いしているので、
Since we had a pro prepare this,
何が出てくるでしょうか？！
what will come out?!
ドキドキするな、これ。
This makes me so nervous.
見ていきましょう！お願いします！ / お願いします。
Let's check it out! Please bring it out! / Please.
おおー！うっまそうだけど！ / おおー！
Ooh! It looks so good, but...! / Ooh!
めちゃくちゃうまそう！ / うーまそう！
That looks crazy good! / Looks soooo good!
え、ちょっと待って、ベジマイトを発見できないですよね、ちょっと。まあ...
Wait, I can't spot the Vegemite at all. Well...
すごい。 / どっか入ってる？
Amazing. / Is it in there somewhere?
これが一応、牛タントルティーヤ。
This is, for the record, a Beef Tongue Tortilla.
トルティーヤ！It's like a tortilla, it's like a wrap!
Tortilla! It's like a tortilla, it's like a wrap!
はいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right.
最近はね、タコスも流行ってますからね。 / 流行ってますからね。へえー。
Tacos are really popular these days too. / They are, yeah. Wow.
There's like this really... いや、ソースめっちゃいい匂いするっすね。
There's like this really... Man, the sauce smells so good!
ソースをかけたらいいのかな、これは。
I guess we should pour the sauce over it.
じゃ、ちょっと食べてみます。 / 食べてみ... はい！
Well, let's give it a taste. / Give it a... yes!
じゃあロベルさん、行っちゃってよ。
Alright, Roberu-san, dig in!
ちゃんとしてるな！いただきます。
It looks so legit! Bon appétit.
ちょっと、ちゃんとして...
Wait, legit...?
あ、行ってる行ってる行ってる！
Oh, he's taking a bite!
うん。 / お、食べてます。
Mm. / Oh, he's eating.
じゃあ僕もいただきます。
Then I'll dig in too.
お、いい感じだぞ、ロベルさんが。うんうんうん。
Oh, Roberu-san looks like he's enjoying it. Mm-hmm.
ロベさん、どうよ？
Robe-san, how is it?
いや、あのね...
Well, you see...
言っていっすか？全然美味しいっす。
Can I be honest? It's totally delicious.
ええ？！
Really?!
ベジマイトがどこにいるかわかんないです。
I can't even tell where the Vegemite is.
え、それ合ってるの？（笑）
Wait, is that how it's supposed to be?
わかんないです。 / Baeさんも美味い？
I don't know. / Is it good for you too, Bae-san?
うまい！うまい！
It's good! Delicious!
ええー！美味い？
Ehh?! It's good?
そっか、今二人が先に食べてリアクション見てから食べようと思って。
I see. I wanted to see your reactions first before trying it myself.
ありがと。 / じゃあ大丈夫そうだね。いただきます。
Thanks. / Looks safe then. Down the hatch!
こいつ...
This guy...
うーーーまい！！
It's sooo good!!
ええ？！ / 本当に。
What?! / Seriously.
ベジマイトがどこにいるかマジで分からん。
I honestly have no clue where the Vegemite is.
で、これ... これはまたプロの方からのあれがあるんですかね？
And so... is there another comment from the pro?
We have a comment from the food coordinator.
はい、これは、牛タンというのは塩レモンだれでよく食べるところから発想いたしました。
Yes, "This was inspired by how beef tongue is often eaten with salted lemon sauce."
レモン塩だれの塩部分をベジマイトにしました。
"I substituted the salt part of the lemon salt sauce with Vegemite."
へええー！！
Whoaaa!!
The idea came from the way beef tongue is commonly enjoyed with a salted lemon sauce, so instead...
...salt in the lemon sauce, we replaced it with Vegemite!
天才すぎる！
I'm such a genius!
あ、そう？
Ah, really?
なるほど、塩味だけを残したんだ。
I see, so you just kept the saltiness.
いや、でもベジマイト風味はあるじゃないですか？
No, but you can still taste the Vegemite flavor, right?
あの確かに食べ終わった後ちょっと...
Yeah, for sure, after finishing it, a little bit...
It has like a slight like, it's like a refreshing breeze of Vegemite.
なんか優しい風みたいな。
Like a gentle breeze.
確かにね。
True.
ベジマイトが優しい風になることあるんだね。
Vegemite can actually turn into a gentle breeze, huh?
そうです！
That's right!
ベジマイトだけ食べたら岩で殴られたみたいな衝撃あったけど...
When I ate just Vegemite, it felt like getting hit with a rock, but...
こんな優しい風に調理できるんだね、ベジマイトってね。
...you can actually cook Vegemite into such a gentle breeze, huh?
ベジマイトは優しいです。
Vegemite is gentle.
すご！これは美味しいですね。
Amazing! This is really delicious.
ね。
Yeah.
では続いて、界人さん！
Now next up, Kaito-san!
はい！
Yes!
We gonna move on with Ishikawa Kaito-san's...
We're going to move on with Ishikawa Kaito-san's...
ingredients!
どんなものを選びました？
What did you choose?
じゃあ僕が選んだ食材、こちらです！ドーン！
Well then, the ingredient I chose is this right here! Boom!
何？何ですか？
What? What is it?
納豆です！
It's natto!
いやー！キター！
Nooo! Here it is!
きちー！きちー！
Tough! That's rough!
あれ？納豆好き...
Wait, you like natto...
納豆は好きよ。ですよね？
I do like natto. / Right?
もう癖強には癖強ぶつけたら、こう何だろう、対消滅みたいにするんじゃないかなと思って。
I thought if we clash strong taste with strong taste, they'd kind of annihilate each other.
I like the way he thinks! I like the way he thinks!
もうめちゃくちゃ素晴らしいと思います。
I think that's super wonderful.
そう、こちらを選ばせていただきました。日本の文化をぶつけてやるぜ！
Right, so I chose this. Let's clash with Japanese culture!
This is Japanese culture. Yes.
まあ、without further ado, what is the professional chef gonna do this time?
Well, without further ado, what is the professional chef going to do this time?
見ていきましょう！お願いします！
Let's take a look! Please go ahead!
どうなっちゃうの納豆は？
What's going to happen to the natto?
おおー！えー！？
Ooh! Eh?!
なんだこれ！どういうこと？どういうこと！？どういうことだ？
What is this?! What does this mean? What do you mean?! What does this mean?
うまそう！
Looks delicious!
え、何何何何？これどういう食べ物？
Eh, what what what what? What kind of food is this?
あの、発酵生春巻き？
Um, fermented fresh spring rolls?
発酵生春巻...生春巻きだ！
Fermented fresh spring roll... It's a fresh spring roll!
生春巻き。発酵生春巻きって言葉も初めて聞きましたけど。
Fresh spring roll. I've never heard the term "fermented fresh spring roll" before, though.
うわー、めっちゃトロトロしてるー！
Whoa, it looks super gooey!
おお、これもう一口で行くか。
Oh, should I just eat it in one bite?
いっちゃってよ、ベーさん。
Go for it, Bae-san.
はい！じゃあつけていただきます。
Okay! I'll dip it and eat.
いただきます。
Bon appétit.
うわ、めっちゃくちゃ... It's so slimy. いただきます。
Whoa, it's so... It's so slimy. Bon appétit.
界人さん。 え？ 先に言っとく。 うん。
Kaito-san. / Eh? / I'll tell you right now. / Yeah.
明確にいる。 いる？
It's definitely in there. / It is?
いる？
It is?
んー、奴がいる。
Mmm, that guy is in there.
いるなあ！
It's totally in there!
いるー！ いる。
It's in there! / It is.
いや、これソースにいるね。
No, it's in the sauce.
あ、ソースか。 うん。
Ah, in the sauce? / Yeah.
あれ？全然味しないすけど。
Huh? I don't taste it at all though.
え？
Eh?
うまい！
It's delicious!
え？あれ、ちょいして？ いや、いるよ。
Eh? Wait, what? / No, it's there.
納豆に押しかってるぐらいまである。 うん、わかる。
It's almost overpowering the natto. / Yeah, I get that.
相当だよ。 めちゃくちゃ美味しい。 うん。美味しい。
It's pretty intense. / It's super delicious. / Yeah. It's delicious.
普通に発酵同士なので相性がいいとのことでございます。
It turns out since they're both fermented, they actually go really well together.
へえー！やっぱ塩味があるので、何かのソースにできるとやっぱ... 塩味なんすね。
Whoa! Since it has saltiness, being able to turn it into a sauce... / It's the saltiness, huh.
納豆のタレ...なるほど、納豆のタレをベジマイトにしたらいいなと思い、マヨベースにしてその中にベジマイト入りタレを作りました。
Natto sauce... I see, thinking it would be good to replace the natto sauce with Vegemite, we made a mayo-based sauce with Vegemite mixed in.
おおー！なるほど！ うーん！
Ooh! I see! / Mmm!
So, Vegemite is very nice and salty, figured it could work as a base for a sauce, had the idea of replacing the sauce that comes with natto with Vegemite, made a mayonnaise-based sauce and mixed Vegemite into it!
うまい！ あ、うまい！
Delicious! / Ah, delicious!
食えちゃうんだよね。 まあね！
You can just totally eat it. / Well, yeah!
食えちゃうってどういうことすか？
What do you mean "you can eat it"?
うまいんだよ。 いや、美味しいです！
It is delicious. / No, it's delicious!
This is so good. Oh my god. もうキラキラ！
This is so good. Oh my god. Just shining!
へえー！
Whoa!
最後に行きますが...
Moving on to the last one...
うん、はい。
Yeah, okay.
食事中の... 何？何笑ってんだよ、おい。
During meals... / What? What are you laughing at, hey?
何ニヤニヤ...何ヘラヘラしてんだよ。
Why are you smirking... What are you giggling about?
食事後って普段何食べております？
What do you usually eat after a meal?
あ、食事の後？ はい！
Ah, after a meal? / Yes!
まあ、デザートみたいな。 デザートですね！
Well, like dessert. / Dessert, right!
お、おう、おう。 次は僕が選んだ食べ物になります。
O-oh, yeah. / Next is the food that I chose.
We have reached the final dish, and normally at the end of every meal you do have dessert.
オーストラリアトレジャー。
Australia treasure.
宝物を組んだらどうなるかと思って...
Thinking what would happen if we combine treasures...
宝物を２つ？ 宝物２つを組んだら...
Two treasures? / If we combine two treasures...
どうなっちゃうか、ちょっとめちゃくちゃあの、気になったんで、ええと最後の...
...what will happen? I was super, um, curious, so the final...
もの、あの材料はこちらになります。
...item, the ingredient is this one right here.
何？ こわ。な、何？
What? / Scary. Wh-What is it?
ティムタムです。
It's Tim Tam.
だ、誰？誰？ 何？ 誰、ティムタムは？
Wh-Who? Who? / What? / Who is Tim Tam?
その宝知らないわ。 誰、ティムタム？
I don't know that treasure. / Who is Tim Tam?
え？ティムタム知らないすか？ 知らないよ、ティムタム。
Eh? You don't know Tim Tam? / I don't know Tim Tam.
えー！これはオーストラリアのめちゃくちゃ有名なチョコレート、まあビスケット、ウエハース...
Ehh?! This is Australia's super famous chocolate, well, biscuit, wafer...
おおー！なるほど。 あれあれ、ティムタムです。
Ooh! I see. / That one, it's Tim Tam.
ティムタムってお菓子ね。 お菓子！
Tim Tam is a sweet snack, right? / A sweet snack!
それを、じゃあ、くれるんだ？その、ベジマイトとかじゃなくて、単体でね？
So, you're going to give us that, then? Like, not with Vegemite, just by itself, right?
嬉しいね、ありがたいね。お土産でね。
That's nice, we're grateful. As a souvenir.
美味しい、美味しいんだろうね。
It must be really tasty.
美味しい、ありがとう！クッキー、ビスケットはね。
Delicious, thank you! Cookies and biscuits, that is.
本当に呼んでくれてありがとう、今日は。ありがとう。
Really, thank you for inviting us today. Thank you.
ご褒美だよね、頑張った俺たちに対する。
It's a reward, right? For working so hard.
ということで、ちょっとあのプロの方だったからまああの、ティムタムプラスベジマイト...
And so, since they're a professional, well, Tim Tam plus Vegemite...
本当に、あの、ま、美味しく作ってくれたのかなって...
I wonder if they made it truly delicious...
どういうことだよ！
What do you mean by that?!
...思いまして / なんで混ぜんだよ
...I was wondering, so... / Why mix them up?!
...ので、you know, it's a pro chef, I wanted to see what they can do. And I believe in their skills as a pro chef.
...so you know, it's a pro chef, I wanted to see what they can do. And I believe in their skills as a pro chef.
見ていきましょう！お願いします！ / ほい！ / ええ...
Let's take a look! Here it comes! / Alright! / Whoa...
うわ！えっ？！
Whoa! Huh?!
おっとっとっと...どういうこと？
Hold on, hold on... What's going on here?
ティラミス？ / ティラミスじゃん！
Tiramisu? / It's tiramisu!
え、うまそ...え？どういうこと？ / え、美味しそう！
Wait, it looks so good... Huh? What's going on? / Wow, looks delicious!
まあちょっと一旦、ベジ案、発案者だしさ... / そうだね、先に... / そうそうそう、食べてみてよ
Well, since Bae came up with the idea... / Right, you go first... / Yeah, go ahead and try it.
はい、いただきます / うん
Okay, thank you for the food! / Yep.
え、でもなんか...完璧にめちゃくちゃ美味し... / うん、すごいな
Wait, but it looks perfectly delicious... / Yeah, impressive.
うわー！これがベジマイト入ってる？
Whoa! There's Vegemite in this?
いただきます / いや分からん、もう警戒心が強くなりすぎてるだけかもしれん
Bon appétit! / I don't know, maybe we're just being way too overly cautious.
え、普通に... / え、普通にティラミス... / ティラミスだよね？ / ティラミスじゃん！
Wait, it looks totally like normal tiramisu... / It's tiramisu, right? / It really is tiramisu!
いただきます / はい
Here I go! / Go for it.
ん？ん？ん？ん？ん？なんか不思議そうな顔してない？
Huh? Doesn't she have a puzzled look on her face?
あれ？本当に入ってます？ベジマイト
Wait, is there really Vegemite in this?
え？入ってる... / 入ってるそうですよ / 美味しい！
Huh? Apparently there is. / It's delicious!
え？ / 普通にティラミスやん！
Huh? / It's just like a regular tiramisu!
え、普通にティラミス？ / いただきます / え、じゃあいただきます / 普通にティラミス？ / え、どこに？
Just regular tiramisu? / Here goes! / Well then, bon appétit! / Really? / Wait, where is it?
あれ？ベーちゃんが一番分かってないまであるからな、ベジマイト
Wait, Bae-chan might be the one who understands Vegemite the least.
ん？ん？
Hmm? Hmm?
マジで、え？ベジマイトがいるのか？
Seriously, huh? Is Vegemite actually in here?
かすかに塩味あって、うま！あ、いるわ！
There's a subtle saltiness, it's so good! Oh, it's there!
あ、いる！ / いる！え、うま！
Oh, it's there! / It's there! Whoa, so good!
え、美味しい！ / めっちゃ美味いんだけど、これ！え？うっま！
Wow, delicious! / This is crazy good! Huh?! So yummy!
Oh my god!
え？これお店出しましょう / はい！本当に！ / ほんと、We need We need a copyright, we need a patent, oh my god!
Huh? We should serve this in restaurants! / Yes! Truly! / We need a copyright, we need a patent, oh my god!
ガチで美味い！ / すごい、ガチで美味い
It's seriously delicious! / Amazing, it's genuinely good.
えー、Tim Tamと合う料理は思いつくのが大変でした。すみませんでした！本当に / ほらそうだ
It was really tough to think of a dish that pairs well with Tim Tams. I'm sorry! Truly. / See, told you!
Tim Tam自体はコーヒーが合いそうと思ったのでティラミスにしました。はい / あー、うんうん
Since Tim Tams go well with coffee, I turned it into a tiramisu! Yes. / Ah, I see.
Tim Tamのクッキーはサクサクを活かしたいので、Tim Tamを砕いてベジマイトを...
I wanted to keep the crispy texture of the Tim Tam cookie, so I crushed it and added Vegemite...
染み込ませる？ / 染み込ませ... / あ、Tim Tamを砕いてその中にベジマイト入れて混ぜてそれをやってるんだ
Soaked it? / Soaked it... / Ah, you crushed Tim Tams, mixed in Vegemite, and made it that way!
So, apparently it was really hard to think of a dish that would pair well with Tim Tam. Um, but Tim Tam goes well with coffee! Decided to make it Tiramisu. Also wanted to keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam, so I crushed it up, soaked it with Vegemite...
すっげえ美味い！すっげえ美味い！
It's super good! Super good!
しかも普通のティラミスより美味しくなってて... / ね！ / でしょー！
Plus, it tastes even better than a regular tiramisu! / Right? / See?!
塩味が良い味出してる / そう！ / 甘みが際立つというか / まさしく！
The saltiness brings out great flavor. / Exactly! / It really enhances the sweetness. / Precisely!
で、かつ、なんか生クリームの濃さとかがこの塩味によってちょっと中和される感もあって、めちゃくちゃくどくない
And the saltiness balances out the richness of the whipped cream, so it's not heavy at all.
ねー！ / うまい！うまい！
Right?! / Delicious! Delicious!
ティラミスにすることによってコーヒーの香りと苦味で、そのTim Tamのすっごい甘い感じも、程よくまろやかになって...
By making it tiramisu, the coffee aroma and bitterness smooth out the intense sweetness of the Tim Tam nicely...
てか、Tim Tamが美味いんじゃないの？これ / いやいや、美味しい... / これTim Tam美味いんじゃない？
Wait, isn't it just that Tim Tams are delicious? / No no, it's tasty... / Aren't Tim Tams just great on their own?
でも、Tim Tamの美味しさをちょっとね、浄化したの、もうベジマイトのおかげなんで！ / うんうんうん
But elevating the deliciousness of Tim Tam is all thanks to Vegemite! / Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All because of Vegemite, Tim Tam's deliciousness have been, you know...
これ美味！ / うーん！ / すごいわ
This is delicious! / Mmm! / Amazing.
え？プロってすごいな！あのベジマイトをこんなにできるの？
Huh? Professionals are incredible! Turning that Vegemite into this?
「あのベジマイト」やめてください！ / ごめんなさい
Please stop saying "that Vegemite"! / I'm sorry!
めっちゃ食ってますね。よかったです
You're really eating it up. I'm glad!
完食です！ / あ！
Finished it all! / Ah!
あのね、全部美味かったな。総じて。今のとこ3個食べたけど
You know, everything was delicious overall, out of the three we've eaten so far.
えっと、ちょっと最後に美味しさっていうか、もう三ツ星の評価というか、ちょっとやりたくて...
Um, so at the end, I'd like to do a 3-star rating evaluation for deliciousness...
I want to rate all of the different dishes.
どれが一番美味しかったかちょっとね、決めたいので...
I want to decide which one tasted the best, so...
今ままで食べた中で、どれが一番ベジマイトとの相性が良かったかってことね？ / そうですね！ / なるほど
Out of everything we ate, which one went best with Vegemite, right? / Exactly! / I see.
じゃあまず、えっと先輩の牛タンですね
First up is Senpai's beef tongue dish!
何、何星ですか？ How many stars are we giving the gyutan?
How many stars are we giving the gyutan?
うーん... / おおー...
Hmm... / Oh...
俺は、二ツ星かな？
For me, two stars, maybe?
Two stars? / まあ俺も2かな？2になるかな
Two stars? / Well, I'd say 2 as well. Probably a 2.
いや、僕も2だと思いましたね。いやめちゃくちゃ美味しかったです / うん / 美味しかった
Yeah, I thought 2 as well. It was super delicious! / Yeah. / Very tasty.
次が、春風さんの納豆ですね / 納豆ね
Next is Harukaze-san's natto dish. / The natto, right.
あ、一ツ星かな
Ah, one star, maybe.
ごめん、俺も一ツ星かな / えー！ / うん
Sorry, one star for me too. / What?! / Yeah.
自分は2.5なんですけど
I gave it 2.5 though!
あれ？ / え？ / めちゃくちゃ美味しい！
Wait? / Huh? / It's super delicious!
いや、美味しかったんだけど、ベジマイトがいた / 美味しかった、美味しかった
Well, it was good, but Vegemite was definitely there. / It was tasty, it was tasty.
そうなの、なんか風邪じゃなかった、ベジマイトが。まだなんか小石ぐらいあった
Right, the Vegemite wasn't just a slight breeze—it was still like a pebble.
ま、確かにそうですね。あれが好きだったかもしれないっす、自分は / うん、なるほど
Well, true enough. Personally, I might have actually liked that. / Hmm, I see.
で、最後僕のティラミス、Tim Tam何星ですか？
And finally, for my Tim Tam tiramisu, how many stars?
3 / 3！3！
3. / 3! 3!
僕も3！勝ったー！
I give it 3 too! I won!!
三ツ星すぎ！
Total 3-star material!
ベジマイトがTim Tamの甘さを活かしてた
The Vegemite really brought out the sweetness of the Tim Tam.
ですよね！ / うん / いや、流石ベジマイトです
Right?! / Yeah. / As expected of Vegemite!
もうこのティラミスが、もう二つの宝が合わさったことによって、もうたった一つの大秘宝になってた！
When those two treasures combined in this tiramisu, it created the ultimate One Piece treasure!
あいつオーストラリアから何かもらおうとしてるな
That guy is definitely trying to get something from Australia!
僕はアニメ声優をやってましてね！ええ！
I happen to work as an anime voice actor, you know! Yes indeed!
でも美味しかった、これ
Still, it was really delicious!
すごく...
Really...
企画、まあこういう感じだったんですけど...
Well, that was the segment, but...
ちょっとベジマイトの、あの、最初のまあ、イメージ変わりました？
did your initial image of Vegemite change at all?
ああー、最初に食べてみてからと？
Ah, compared to when we first tasted it?
感想、まあね、
Impressions, well,
感想変わりました？もしかして。
did your impressions change perhaps?
なんか物によってはというか...
Rather than depending on the dish...
こんなにもやり方次第で、ベジマイトの味が変化していくものなのかとか...
I realized how much the taste of Vegemite can change depending on how you prepare it...
なんか色々な使い方があるんだなあっていう意味でびっくりはしたね。
I was surprised to see there are so many ways to use it.
うん、すごくびっくりしました、僕は。ベジマイト。
Yeah, I was really surprised by it. Vegemite, that is.
Roberu-senpai is shocked.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ベジマイト大好き。I like Vegemite.
I love Vegemite. I like Vegemite.
I like Vegemite.
いや、likeじゃない。I love Vegemite.
No, not like. I love Vegemite.
あ、あざっす！
Ah, thanks!
Yeah!
はい。ありがとうございます！
Yes. Thank you very much!
で、Hideさんは？
And what about you, Hide-san?
俺は... やっぱこう最初の印象はもういろんな味がすることで、こう... なんだろう、びっくりするなー...
For me... my initial impression was being surprised by tasting so many different flavors...
みんなショックやん！
Everyone was in shock!
っていうなんか印象だったんだけど...
That was kind of my impression, but...
こんなにいろんな調理の仕方すると...
when you cook it in all these different ways...
ベジマイトのそのいろんな味がするっていういいところを、こう、ちょっとずつこう拾っていけるんだと思って。
I realized you can bring out the good parts of Vegemite's multifaceted flavor bit by bit.
無限の可能性がある食材だなというふうに思いましたね。
I felt that it's an ingredient with endless possibilities.
好きですか？好きになりました？
Do you like it? Did you come to like it?
ああ... いや、まあ、ね？
Ah... well, you know?
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
あの、あんまり俺、そう...
Well, I don't really...
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
Yes.
え？
What?
はい。
Yes.
え？好きになりました？
Eh? Did you come to like it?
はい！
Yes!
あざっす！
Thanks!
えっと、まあ、皆もね、気になったらもう是非是非ベジマイトを自分を買って、自分でちょっとね...
Well, if everyone is curious, please definitely buy Vegemite yourself and try...
If you experiment with Vegemite...
あんまり無理すんなよ。
Don't push yourselves too hard.
調理技術に自信があれば。
If you're confident in your cooking skills.
If you want to find your own ways to enjoy Vegemite, I feel like, you know, it'll, it'll be such a great experience.
瓶はちょっと... 瓶はちょっと...
The jar is a bit... The jar is a bit...
まあまあ、何はともあれ Baeちゃん、本当に...
Well, anyway, Bae-chan, really...
マジで5周年おめでとう！
Happy 5th anniversary, seriously!
おめでとうございます！ライブ開催もね！
Congratulations! For the live concert too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おめでと！おめでと！
Congrats! Congrats!
ありがとうございます！来てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much for coming!
ライブ頑張ってね！
Good luck with the live!
Thank you to the two of them for coming!
I can't believe this is how I'm celebrating my 5th year anniversary, but I'm so glad it is!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
Thank you very much!
じゃあ、せーの！
Alright, ready, set!
おつベジマイトー！
Otsu-begimaito~!
三ツ星！
Three stars!
良い子は真似しないでね。
Good kids, don't try this at home.
And with that, we're almost at the end of my anniversary stream!
I hope you all had fun today!
いやもう、終わりたくないね！
Aw man, I really don't want it to end!
本当に5周年ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for 5 years!
Thank you so much for all the support for five years!
We're not done yet!
まだね、お知らせ1個残ってます！なんと...
We still have one announcement left! And that is...
グッズ出ます！
We have merch coming!
We still have the last announcement! 5th Anniversary merch!
We've got some really cool merch this time, too!
Please check it out! どうぞ！
Please check it out! Here you go!
5th Anniversary merch!
Of course, it had to be the Monochrome Dancer, um, and Rat Dancer.
This is the Best Oshi merch!
This beautiful artwork was done by Hyde-sensei.
ええと、Hyde先生に描いていただきました！
Hyde-sensei drew this for us!
今回のグッズのテーマはまあやっぱり今年発表したモノクロームダンサー衣装と...
The theme for this merch is of course the Monochrome Dancer outfit revealed this year...
ええと、バックダンサーのまあ、お二人ですね。はい！
and the two back dancers. Yes!
あの、let's go through each item one by one!
Let's go through each item one by one!
First up is this!
First is the acrylic stand. "Best Oshi" acrylic stand.
ベスト推しアクリルスタンドですね！
It's the "Best Oshi" acrylic stand!
It's so cool! Um, it features the amazing artwork that Hyde did, and I think it features... it's all the best oshi...
まあベスト推し僕ですよね？僕ですね。僕ですね。はい。
Well, the best oshi is me, right? It's me. It's me. Yes.
Yes, of course. The best oshi, everyone's favorite oshi, is me.
But it does have the two back dancers in the back 'cause I know you guys love them.
I'm so obsessed with how it turned out.
いや、めちゃくちゃかっこいい感じになったと思います！
Yeah, I think it turned out super cool!
Then next up is...
The "Rat Dancer" Jacket! Woohoo!
やっとですね！Rat Dan... Dancer Jacket is becoming official merch!
Finally! The Rat Dancer Jacket is becoming official merch!
グッズになりました、ジャケットが！
The jacket has become official merchandise!
いやあ、本当に素晴らしい！
Man, it's truly wonderful!
We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
ちょっとね、あの、このジャケットは着用しやすいようちょっと調整をしたんですけど...
We made some adjustments so this jacket is easy to wear...
本当にかっこいいジャケットになったと思います！
and I think it turned out to be a really cool jacket!
なんとね、あの、this time the 5th Anniversary merch is...
And, this time the 5th Anniversary merch...
it doesn't have as many items just because I know there's a lot happening.
doesn't have as many items just because I know there's a lot happening.
We've got the album, you know, and also we've got the live and everything.
So it's only these two items,
but if you pick up the complete merch set, you also get this!
You will get a replica sticker with a signature and an exclusive ASMR voice pack as a special bonus.
Thank you so much for always supporting me.
えっと、もしね、今回ちょっとね、あの、色... たくさん告知とかお知らせがあったんですけど...
Um, this time there were a lot of announcements and notices, but...
と、今回の必須、あの、5周年グッズは2点になります。
And the 5th anniversary goods this time are two items.
えっと、もしセット買ってくれている方に
And for those who buy the full set,
複製サイン入りのステッカーと、ASMRボイスが特典でついてきます！
it comes with a duplicated autograph sticker and an ASMR voice pack as bonus perks!
The title of the voice pack is "Bae My Model!"
Uh, we check out the sample of the rat dancer jacket together,
and there's even a scene where we actually recorded using the real jacket sample,
so I hope you give it a listen!
えっと、まあ、こちらのボイスのタイトルは「ボクのモデルになって！」
Um, well, the title of this voice pack is "Bae My Model!"
いや、先ほどね、あの、紹介した、えー、ジャケットのサンプルを使って
We used the jacket sample I showed earlier
一緒になんかね、あの、ボイスのシチュエーションを作ったというか、まあ、あの、収録しました。
to create the situation and record the voice pack together.
あ、恥ずかしいながら、ぜひ聴いててください。
It's a bit embarrassing, but please definitely give it a listen.
Uh, you can access the shop directly from YouTube, so be sure to check it out!
YouTubeからショップへアクセスできるので、チェックしてくださーい！
You can access the shop from YouTube, so please check it out!
ふぁ！
Phew!
That was the actual final announcement,
but before I go, there's one more thing I wanted to do with you all.
And in order to do that, I need to first... HENSHIN!
あはははは！はい、アイドルBae来ました。
Ahahaha! Yes, Idol Bae is here!
Uh, I just wanted to sing one song before we end today's stream.
Um, I just want to say thank you so much for 5 years.
I'll continue doing my best. Thank you so much for everything you've given me,
and I will do my best.
えー、まあ、5年間本当にありがとうございました。
Um, well, thank you so much for these 5 years.
ちょっと最後にね、1曲歌いたいなと思ってます。
I'd like to sing one last song at the end.
気持ちを込めて、これからも頑張りたいと思いますので、最後の1曲聴いてください！
Putting my feelings into it and doing my best moving forward, please listen to this final song!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
誇り高きアイドルだー！
I'm a proud idol!
私のこと知ってますか？ 可愛く見えてますか？
Do you know who I am? Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな うまく歌えてますか？
What do you think of my singing? Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか 可愛く見えてますか？
My costume, my makeup... Do I look cute in them?
振付とかファンサとかも 喜んでもらえますか？
My choreography and fan service... Are you enjoying them?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands are getting cold, and my legs are shaking.
それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
Even so, I want to keep fighting, because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Saying words like "just an idol"—
見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say that when you haven't even watched!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted!
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image on me!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The phrase "just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...is what I hate most in this world!
プライベート 見えないから 分からないと思います
You can't see my private life, so you probably wouldn't know,
性格とか 悪い方です 騙しちゃっていますか？
but my personality is kind of bad. Did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です 本気なんです ありのままの私を
But I'm serious, I really mean it! The real me, just as I am—
好きになって 推して下さい それってワガママですか？
Please love me and support me. Is that asking for too much?
きっと可愛くない 全部分かってる
I'm sure I'm not cute; I know it all too well.
それでも好かれてたい アイドルだから
Even so, I want to be loved, because I'm an idol.
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things.
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate making excuses all the time too.
“こんなもんか”という言葉を
Saying words like "is this all?"—
軽々しく口にするな
Don't utter them so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't go setting limits on me!
笑い者になんてするな
Don't make a laughingstock out of me!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
The phrase "just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...is what I hate most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwind!
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol...
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it!
応援がなければ 活動できない
Without your support, I can't keep going.
好きな事ばかりじゃ 生きてはいけない
I can't live doing only what I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし
I was supposed to give you energy, but I'm always receiving it instead.
恩返しできる日まで 待ってて
Until the day I can repay you... wait for me!
待っててね！
Wait for me, okay?!
12月！約束だ！
December! That's a promise!
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even if the cheers fade, even if people get bored of me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
I still want to keep smiling, because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of my fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって
and always with the love of my family...
生きてる
...I'm living as...
アイドル！
...an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of us!
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon too!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Don't say words like "just an idol"...
見てもいないくせに言うな
...when you haven't even watched!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't treat hard work as a given!
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image on us!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...are what I hate most in this world!
ありがとうねー！
Thank you!
MV見て！MV見て！
Watch the MV! Watch the MV!
Thank you everyone for being here!
Don't forget to check out YouTube Music Weekend right after this!
And also give a lot of love to I FOUND ME and me!
この後も見ててね！
Keep watching after this, okay?
頑張るから！頑張るから！
I'll do my best! I'll do my best!
応援して、よろしくお願いします！
Please support me, thank you so much!
Thank you so much for 5 years!
I'll keep doing my best!
Bye-bye!
ほんとうに... ほんとうに ありがとう♡
[Text: Thank you so, so much...♡]